In this segment, I want to tell you about
another form of encryption, called format
在这一节，我想跟大家讨论另一种形式的加密 保格式加密
preserving encryption. This is again
something that comes up in practice quite
这也是一种在实际中经常见到的加密方式
often, especially when it comes to
encrypting credit card numbers. And, so,
特别是用来对信用卡卡号进行加密
let's see how it works. Remember that a
typical credit card number is sixteen
因此 让我们来看看它是如何工作的 记住 典型的信用卡卡号一般是16位数字的
digits, broken into four blocks of four
digits each. You've probably heard before
以每4位为一组分成4组 大家以前可能听说过
that the first six digits are what's
called the BIN number, which represent the
前6位被称为BIN码 代表了发行方的ID
issuer ID. For example, all credit cards
issued by VISA always start with the digit
举个例子 所有的VISA信用卡通常都以数字4为开头
four; all credit cards issued by
MasterCard start with digits 51 to 55, and
而所有的MasterCard信用卡都以数字51到55为开头 等等
so on and so forth. The next nine digits
are actually the account number that is
接下来的9位是事实上就是每个消费者所持有的账户数字
specific to the, to the particular
customer and the last digit is a check sum
最后一位则是校验和
that's computed from the previous fifteen
digits. So there are about 20,000 BIN
是由前15位数字计算得到的这里有大约20000个BIN码
numbers and so if you do the calculation
it turns out there are about 2 to the 42
所以如果你计算一下会发现大约有2的42次方可能的信用卡号
possible credit card numbers which
corresponds to about 42 bits of
相应的你需要编码42位信息
information that you need to encode if you
want to represent a credit card number
如果你想准确的表示信用卡卡号
compactly. Now the problem is this.
Suppose we wanted to encrypt credit card
现在的问题是 假设我们想加密信用卡卡号
numbers, so that when the user swipes the
credit card number at the point of sale
使用户在销售终端上刷卡时
terminal, namely at the, you know,
the merchant's cash register. The cash
比如 在商家的现金登记处
register, this is called a point of sale
terminal, goes ahead and encrypts the
现金登记处是一种销售终端
credit card number using a key k and
it's encrypted all the way until it goes
首先使用密钥k机密信用卡卡号 并始终保持加密
to the acquiring bank or maybe even beyond
that, maybe even all the way when it goes
直到银行 甚至是VISA要用的时候
to Visa. Now, the problem is that these
credit card numbers actually pass through
现在的问题是这些信用卡号 事实上经历了许多许多处理节点
many, many, many processing points. All of
them expect to get basically something
它们都希望获得某些基本的
that looks like a credit card number as a
result. So if we simply wanted to encrypt
看起来像是信用卡号的信息作为结果
something at the end point, at one end
point, and decrypt it at the other end
所以如果我们只想在一个终端加密 在另一个终端解密
point, it's actually not that easy because
if all we did was encrypt it using AES,
这实际上并不那么容易 因为如果我们全部所做的仅仅是使用AES加密
even if we just used deterministic AES,
the output of the encrypted credit card
即使用的是确定的AES 加密输出后的信用卡号将会是128位的分组
number would be 128 bit block. Sixteen
bytes that would be, that would need to be
16字节一组 将会被从一个系统发送到下一个系统
sent from one system to the next, until it
reaches its destination. But each one of
直到到达它的目的地
these processors, then, would have to be
changed, because they're all expecting to
但是这些处理节点每个都必须改变 因为它们都希望获得信用卡卡号
get credit card numbers. And so the
question is, can we encrypt at the cash
所以问题是 我们能否在现金登记处加密
register, such that the resulting
encryption itself looks like a credit card
使得加密结果本身看上去像一个信用卡卡号
number. And as a result, none of these
intermediate systems would have to be
因此 这些中间系统都不用做出改变
changed. Only the endpoints would have to
be changed. And in doing so we would
只有端点需要改变 通过这样做
actually obtain end-to-end encryption
without actually having to change a lot of
我们实际上将会获得端到端的加密 而不需要改变大量的沿途软件
software along the way. So the question
then is, again, can we have this mechanism
接下来的问题是 我们能否构造这种叫做保格式加密的机制
called format preserving encryption, where
encrypting a credit card itself produces
加密一个信用卡本身能产生某些类似于信用卡的信息
something that looks like a credit card?
So that's our goal. The encrypted credit
这就是我们的目标
card number should look like a regular
valid credit card number. So this is the
被加密的信用卡卡号应该看起来像一个通常的有效信用卡卡号
goal of format preserving encryption. More
abstractly what it is we're trying to do,
这就是保格式加密的目标 现在我们试图做更抽象的
is basically build a pseudo random
permutation on the set zero to S minus one
在集合｛0，1，……，s-1｝上构建一个伪随机置换  其中s是任意的
for any given S. So for the set of credit
card numbers, S would be roughly, you
所以对于信用卡号的集合来说 s约等于2的42次方
know, two to the 42. In fact, it's gonna
be, not exactly two to the 42. It's gonna
而不是严格的2的42次方
be some funny numbers that's around two to
the 42. And our goal is to build a PRP
它将会是一些接近于2的42次方的有趣的数
that acts exactly on the interval, zero to
S minus one. And what we're given as input
我们的目标是建立一个从0到s-1区间上的PRF
is some PRF, say, something like AES, that
acts on much larger blocks, say, acts on
我们已有的输入是某些PRF 比如AES 它可以处理更大的分组
sixteen byte blocks. So we're trying to,
in some sense, shrink the domain of the
比如16字节的分组 某种意义上 我们试图压缩PRF的定义域
PRF to make it fit the data that we're
given. And the question is basically how
使它与我们已有的数据相吻合 现在的问题是怎么做
to do that. Well, once we have such a
construction we can easily use it to
一旦我们有这样一个机制 就可以很容易的使用它去加密信用卡卡号了
encrypt credit card numbers. What we would
do is we would take the, a given credit
我们将取给定的信用卡卡号
card number. We would encode it such that
now it's represented as a number between
对它加密 使得它能用0到信用卡卡号总数之间的一个数字来表示
zero and the total number of credit card
numbers. Then we would apply our PRP so we
接下来我们应用我们的PRF
would encrypt this credit card number, you
know, using construction number two from
来加密信用卡卡号 使用确定性加密一节里的2号机制
the deterministic encryption segment. And
then we would map the final number back to
然后我们把最终的数字映射为一个正常的值
be a regular, to look like val--, regular,
valid credit card number and then send
一个看起来正常的有效信用卡卡号
this along the way. So this is, this
is again non expanding encryption. The
然后沿途传送 这也是非扩展加密
best we can do, as we said before is to
encrypt using a PRP except again the
我们最多 像前面所讲过的 只能使用PRF加密
technical challenge is we need a PRP that
acts on this particular funny looking set
然而这里技术上的挑战在于 我们需要一个PRF 作用于这个看上去特别有趣的
from zero to S-1 for this prespecified
value of S. So my goal is to show you how
从0到s-1的集合 这里s的值是预先给定的 所以我的目标是教给大家如何去建立这个机制
to construct this and once we see how to
do it, you will also know how to encrypt
一旦我们知道了如何做 大家就会知道如何去加密信用卡卡号
credit card number so that the resulting
cipher text is itself a credit card
使得密文本身也是信用卡卡号
number. So the construction works in two
steps. The first thing we do is we shrink
这个机制分为两步工作 我们做的第一步是将PRF的定义域
our PRF from the set  to the n, say
to the 128 in the case of AES,
集合｛0，1｝的n次方 例如AES的｛0，1｝的128次方
to  to the t where t is the
closest power of two to the value S.
压缩到｛0，1｝的t次方 这里的t是最接近以2为底值为s的对数的数
So say S is some crazy number around two to
the 41. T would basically be then 42
所以说s是一个接近于2的41次方的很大的数 那么t就是42
because that's the closest power of two
that's just above the value S. So the
因为那是最接近以2为底值不小于s的对数的数
construction is basically gonna use the
Luby-Rackoff construction. What we need
它使用了Luby-Rackoff机制
is a PRF F prime that acts on blocks of
size t over two. So imagine for example
我们需要一个PRF F' 作用于一个长度为t/2的分组
in the credit card case, t would be 42
because two to the 42 we said is the
在信用卡这个例子中 t将会是42 因为我们说过2的42次方
closest power of two that's bigger than,
than, than S. S is the number of credit,
是最接近以2为底值不小于s的对数的数 s是所有信用卡号的总和
total number of credit cards. Then we would
need a PRF now that acts on 21-bit
现在我们需要一个PRF作用于21位的输入
inputs. So one way to do that is simply to
take the AES block cipher, treat it as a
一种方法是取AES分组密码
PRF on 128-bit inputs, and then simply
truncate the output to the least
把它当成128位输入的PRF 然后截断输出
significant 21 bits. Okay, so we were
given a 21 bit value. We would append
并取低21为 好的 我们得到了一个21位的值
zeros to it so that we get 128 bits as a
result. We would apply AES to that and
我们在它的末尾添加0得到128位的结果 我们对它应用AES
then we would truncate back to 21 bits.
Now I should tell you that that's actually
然后截断得到21位结果 现在我要告诉大家
a simple way to do it but it's actually
not the best way to do it. There are
这是一个简单的方式 但实际上它并不是最好的方式
actually better ways to truncate a PRF on
n bits to a PRF on t over two bits.
事实上有更好的方法来截断n位PRF得到t位PRF
But for our pur--, for the purposes of this
segment, the truncation method I just said
但是对于我们本节的目标 我刚刚所讲的截断方法以及足够好了
is good enough. So let's just use that
particular method. Okay, so now, we've
所以我们先继续使用这个特别地方法 好的 那么现在
converted our AES block cipher into a PRF
on t over two bits, say, on 21 bits. But
我们已经把AES分组密码转换成了一个t/2位的PRF 例如 21位
what we really want is a PRP. And so what
we'll do is we'll plug our new PRF, F prime,
但我们其实想要的是一个PRP 所以我们要做的是
directly into the Luby-Rackoff
construction. If you remember, this is
把我们的PRF直接带入Luby-Rackoff机制中 如果大家还记得
basically a Feistel construction. We saw
this when we talked about DES. It's a,
这是一个Feistel机制 我们讨论DES时大家见过它
Luby-Rackoff used three rounds, and we
know that this converts a secure PRF into
Luby-Rackoff用了3轮的Feistel网络 我们知道这将一个安全的PRF
a secure PRP on twice the block size. In
other words, we started from a secure PRF
转换为一个安全的两倍大小的PRP 换句话说 我们从一个21位的安全PRF开始
on 21 bits, and that will give us, and
Luby-Rackoff will give us a secure PRF on
Luby-Rackoff会给我们一个安全的42位的PRF
42 bits, which is what we wanted. Now, I
should tell you that the error parameters
这正是我们想要的 现在 我应该告诉你们Luby-Rackoff机制
in the Luby-Rackoff construction are not as
good as they could be. And, in fact, a
的错误参数不像应有的那么好 事实上
better thing to do is to use seven rounds
of Feistel. So in other words, we'll do
更好的方法是使用7轮Feistel 换句话说 我们应该重复7遍
this seven times; every time we'll use a
different key. So you notice, here, we're
每次都用不同的密钥 你应该注意到
only using three keys. We should be using,
we should be doing this seven times using
这里我们用了3个密钥 而我们应该用7种不同的密钥重复7遍
seven different keys. And then there's a
nice result, due to Patarin, that
这样才会有一个好的结果 paratin证明
shows that the seven-round construction
basically has as good an error
7轮的机制基本上有一个最好情况的错误项
terms as possible. So the error terms in
the security theorem will basically be two
所以在这个安全理论中错误项基本上为2^t
to the T. Okay. So now we have a pseudo
random permutation that operates on close
所以我们有在接近2^s个值上操作的一个伪随机置换
power of two to the value of S. But that's
not good enough. We actually want to get a
但这还不够好 事实上 我们想要得到一个
pseudo random permutation on the set zero
to S minus one. So step two will take us
在0到s-1个值上的伪随机置换
down from  to the T, to the actual
set zero to the S minus one that we're
第二步 取^t中的值 映射到 我们真正感兴趣的集合
interested in. And this construction is,
again, really, really cute, so let me show
这个机制真的真的非常有趣 让我来展示
you how it works. So, again, we're given
this PRP that operates on a power of two.
它是怎么工作的 我们有PRP可以置换t位集合中的元素
And we wanna go down to a PRP that
operates on something slightly smaller.
我们想让这个PRP可以在更小的集合上工作
Okay, so here's on the construction works.
Basically we're given input X in the set
这是这个机制的工作方式 我们给定输入X X属于集合
zero to S minus one that we want. And what
we're going to do is we're going to
我们要做的是
iterate the following procedure again
and again. So first of all we map X into
重复迭代以下流程 首先 我们把Ｘ映射到临时变量Y
this temporary variable Y. And now we're
just gonna encrypt the input X and put the
现在我们只要加密输入Ｘ把结果赋给Ｙ
result into Y. If Y is inside of our
target set, we stop and we output Y. If
如果Ｙ在我们的目标设定中　我们结束并输出Ｙ
not we iterate this again and again and
again and again and again until finally Y
不然　我们就再一次次迭代直到
falls into our target set and then we
output that value. So in a picture, let me
最后Ｙ落在我们的目标集合内　然后我们输出值　让我在一张图
explain how this works. So we start from a
point in our target set. And now, now we
中解释它是怎么工作的　我们从目标集合中的一点开始
apply the, the function E and we might be
mapped into this point outside our target
我们用函数Ｅ我们可能会把这个点映射到目标集合以外
set, so we're not gonna stop. So now we
apply the function E again and we might
所以我们不停下来而是再用一次函数Ｅ　我们可能
be mapped into this point and now we apply
the function E again and now all of a
映射到这个点　我们再应用一遍函数Ｅ　突然间我们
sudden we map into this point, and then we
stop, and that's our output. Okay, so
映射到了这个点　然后我们停下来　这就是我们的输出
that's how we map points between from zero
to S minus one, to other points in the
这就是我们在｛０,１……ｓ－１｝间映射点的方法
zero to S minus one. It should be pretty
clear that this is invertible. To invert,
很显然　这是可逆的
all I'll do is I'll just decrypt and walk,
kind of, in the opposite direction. So
逆向　我将解密然后按相反的方向前进
I'll decrypt, and then decrypt, and then
decrypt, until finally, I fall into the
我会解密　解密　再解密　直到最后　值落在设定的范围内
set, zero to S minus one. And that gives
me the inverse of the point that I wanted
这就给我了我想得到的点的逆
to. So this is, in fact, a PRP. The
question is whether it's a secure PRP, and
这其实就是ＰＲＰ　问题是什么时候这是安全的ＰＲＰ
we'll see that in just a minute. But before
that, let me ask you, how many iterations
我们马上来讨论这个问题　但在此之前　我要问大家
do you expect that we're gonna need? And
I wanna remind you again, before I ask you
你估计要使用多少次迭代　在问这个问题前我再提醒大家一次
that question, that, in fact, S is less than
two to the T, but is more than two to the T-1.
事实上　ｓ小于２＾ｔ大于２＾ｔ－１
So in particular S is greater than two to
the T over two. And my question to you
特别的ｓ比2^t的一半大 那么我的问题
now is how many iterations are we gonna
need, on average, until this process converges?
现在变成 我们平均需要多少次迭代 使过程收敛
So the answer is we're going to need two iterations,
答案是我们需要2次迭代
so really just a small
constant number of iterations. And so this
这是一个很小的常数迭代次数 所以这
will give us a very, very efficient
mechanism that will move us down from
将给我们一个很有效的机制
to the T to zero to the S-1. So now
when we talk about security, it turns out
让我们从^t降到 现在我们讨论安全性
this step here is tight. In other words,
there is really no additional security
实际上是这步是紧凑的 换句话说 这没有多余的安全消耗
cost to going down from two to the T to
zero to S-1. And the reason that's true,
从^t降到 原因是
it's actually again a very cute theorem
to prove, but I, I won't do it here. Maybe
这又是一个有趣的理论 我在这里不做证明
I'll leave it as an exercise for you guys
to argue. Which says that if you give me
或许我将把它留作给你们讨论的练习 也就是说
any two sets Y and X, where Y is contained
inside of X, then applying the
你给我任意设定的Y和X Y包含在X内 应用
transformation that we just saw to a
random permutation from X to X actually
我们刚看到的转换 从一个X到X的随机转换出发
gives a random permutation from Y to Y. So
this means that if we started with a truly
我们得到一个从Y到Y的随机转换 这意味着 如果我们用一个真正的
random permutation on X, you'll end up
with a truly random permutation on Y. And
X上的随机转换 你最后得到一个Y上真正的随机转换
since, well, the permutation we're
starting with is indistinguishable from
既然 我们开始时的转换不能与X上的随机转换区分
random on X, we'll end up with a
permutation that's indistinguishable from
我们得到一个不能与Y上置换区分的置换
random on Y. Okay, so this is a very tight
construction and as I said, the first step
正如我所说 这是一个非常紧凑的置换
actually is basically, the analysis is the
same as the Luby-Rackoff analysis. In
第一步其实是寄出的 其分析和Luby-Rackoff的分析相同
fact, it's better to use as I said, the
Patarin analysis using seven rounds. So
事实上 就我来说这更好用 Patarin分析用了7轮
actually here, there's a bit of cost in
security. But, overall, we get a
事实上这里有一些安全的消耗 但总的来说我们
construction that is a secure PRP for
actually, not such good security
得到一个安全PRP机制 虽然安全参数不太好
parameters, but nevertheless, this is a
good secure PRP that we can construct that
但这是我们能构造的较好的安全的
actually will operate on the range zero to
S minus one. This in turn will allow us to
在0到s-1范围内操作的PRP 这反过来会允许我们
encrypt credit card numbers such that the
cipher text looks like a credit card
加密信用卡号使密文形式与信用卡号相同
number. And again, I want to emphasize
that there's no integrity here. The best
再一次强调这里没有完整性
we can achieve here is just
deterministic CPA security. No cipher text
我们能确定的最好的结果是CPA安全
integrity, and no randomness at all. Okay.
So this concludes this module. And as
没有密文完整性 没有任何随机性 这是这块的总结
usual I want to point to a few reading
materials that you can take a look at if
照例 我想指出一些你们可以看的阅读材料
you're interested in learning more about
anything that we discussed in this module.
如果你们有兴趣学习更多关于任何我们在这一章讨论的
So first of all, the HKDF construction
that we talked about for key derivation is
首先 我们讨论密钥推导时 HKDF机制在2010年Hugo Krawczyk 的文章里有描述
described in a paper from 2010 by Hugo
Krawczyk. Deterministic encryption, The
HKDF机制在2010年Hugo Krawczyk 的文章里有描述
SIV mode that we described is discussed in
this paper over here. The EME mode that we
确定性加密 SIV模式在这片论文里有讨论
described that allows us to build a, a
wider block pseudo random permutation is
我们讨论的EME模式 让我们可以构建一个更宽的分组伪随机置换
described in this paper here by Halevi and
Rogaway. Tweakable block ciphers that
在这篇论文里被Halevi和Rogaway讨论
actually led to the XDS mode of operation
that's used for disk encryption is
微调分组密码 引入了用于硬盘加密的XTS模式
described in this paper here. And finally,
a format preserving encryption is described
在这片论文里讨论了 最后 保格式加密在
in this last paper that I point to over
here. Okay so this concludes this module.
我点到的最后这篇论文论文里有讨论 这就是本章总结
And in the next module we gonna start
looking at how to do key exchange.
在下一章 我们将开始讨论密钥转换